Now, let's open our Bibles to Exodus
chapter 20.
And as we do every week, we're going to
read the law.
This is the covenant of God. Exodus 20.
And we're going to begin at verse one.
Exodus 20 and one. Did it Darnell? Go
ahead and read.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God,
I'm a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Sixth
day shalt thou labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shall
not do any work. Thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill, thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
coveret thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not coveret thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man serving, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbors.
Let's turn to John 14. John chapter 14.
We're going to read one verse, verse 15.
John chapter 14 and verse number 15.
You get it, brother? Go ahead and read.
>> If you love me, keep my commandments.
>> Do I need to interpret that?
Let's go to Ecclesiastes chapter 12.
Ecclesiastes
12.
We're going to read verses 13 and 14.
Ecclesiastes 12 13 and 14.
Okay. Go ahead.
Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of man. For God shall bring every work
into judgment with every secret thing
whether it be good or whether it be
evil. Amen. Let's go to our last place.
Revelation 22.
Revelation chapter 22.
We're going to read verses 14 and 15.
Revelation 22 verses 14 and 15.
You get it, brother? Go ahead. Blessed
are they that do his commandments that
they may have right to the tree of life
and may enter in through the gates into
the city. For without are dogs and
sorcerers and whoreongers and murderers
and idolattors and whosoever loveth and
maketh a lie.
So brothers and sisters, we just read
that there's a blessing in doing these
commandments. So I thank God for the
reading of the law. I'm brother
Lawrence.
I'm your teacher for today here in
Detroit. And reading for us today, we
have brother Darnell.
The title of today's lesson is
our God dwells in thick darkness.
Our God dwells in thick darkness.
This helps us
keep the second commandment.
This helps us to keep the second
commandment.
We just read the second commandment.
So I'm going to uh
turn to it and read it
in verse number four
where it says, "Thou should not make
unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them
or serve them. For I, the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation
of them that hate me, and showing mercy
unto thousands of them that love me and
keep my commandments.
So
if the Lord dwells in utter darkness,
I'm not.
So that's why I added that little
addendum to the title that that the Lord
dwelling in thick darkness keeps us from
breaking God's second commandment by
making an image
of him. Although man still has made
images of what they say represents God.
So they are breaking the second
commandment.
So all throughout the scriptures, God's
power and presence are revealed not only
through his words but also through
nature and the fulfillment of prophecy
from the uh
from the darkness
of the plagues in Egypt
to the Lord's appearance to Abra Abraham
and Moses
to the crucifixion of Christ. Each event
each event demonstrates how creation
responds to the creator.
We will look at scriptures that
illustrate the dramatic ways God
manifested himself and fulfilled his
promises,
encouraging us to reflect on the
significance
of these moments in the whole Bible.
So without further ado, we're going to
open up
in Genesis
chapter 15
and we're going to look at God's
presence
and the covenant.
Genesis chapter 15.
And we're going to see God, he's going
to make a covenant with Abram because
the God we serve is a covenant God. And
if he if he not in covenant with you or
you not in covenant with him, he does
not deal with you.
So we're going to pick this up at
Genesis 15 and we're going to start at
verse number 17.
And we're going to notice a few things
as we go through
as the Lord appears to Abram
Abram and makes a covenant with him.
15 and 17. Okay, brother. Go ahead.
>> And it came to pass that when the sun
went down and it was dark.
>> So now it's dark. The sun has gone down
and it is dark.
Go ahead.
>> Behold, a smoking furnace and a burning
lamp that passed between those pieces.
So the Lord had had Abra Abram to uh
slaughter a few animals and to cut them
in half and lay them
across from one another.
And the Lord passed between those
animals.
This was this is what was called in the
old c uh old times cutting a covenant.
That's why the animals were cut in half.
So the Lord did this when it was dark,
after the sun went down, and this
smoking furnace and burning lamp
pass through the pieces or the carcasses
of the animal.
This represented the Lord. Go ahead.
In the same day the Lord made a covenant
with Abram, saying, "Unto thy seed have
I given his land. From the river of
Egypt unto the great river, the river
Euphrates."
>> So you just read the covenant that the
Lord made with Abram. He promised Abram
land,
all the land of Canaan, which was called
the promised land from the river of
Egypt unto the great river of Euphrates.
So, let's go to Exodus
the 19th chapter
and God's going to deal with Moses
and God tells Moses that he will come
down
on Mount Si to meet with the people.
This was after they had been delivered
out of the bondage of Egypt.
God came down and the purpose that he
came down for was to make a covenant
with the children of Israel.
Exodus 19 and we're going to pick it up
in verse number nine. Exodus 19 and
verse number N. When you get it,
brother, go ahead.
And the Lord said unto Moses, "Lo, I
come unto thee in a thick cloud, that
the people may hear when I speak with
thee, and believe thee forever." So, how
did the Lord come down to Moses? He came
down in a thick cloud so that there was
no shape or form that Moses could look
upon to say that this is God.
But he came down and he said he would
speak to the children of Israel that
they may believe him for how long?
Forever.
But then they want to tell you, see this
is in the Old Testament. They want to
tell you the Old Testament has been
fulfilled.
How long is forever?
But go ahead.
>> And Moses told the words of the people
unto the Lord. And the Lord said unto
Moses, "Go unto the people and sanctify
them today and tomorrow, and let them
wash their clothes, and be ready against
the third day. For the third day, the
Lord will come down in the sight of all
the people upon Mount Si." So the Lord
told Moses to go back to the people and
let them wash their clothes.
And he told them also not to come at
their wives
because in the third day he was going to
come down in the sight of all Israel.
Skip down to verse 16.
And it ca
and it came to pass on the third day in
the morning that there were thunders and
lightnings and a thick cloud upon the
mount and the voice of the trumpet
exceeding loud so that all the people
that was in the camp tremble. So the
third day the Lord came down. And when
he came down what did he see? What did
they see? They saw a thick cloud. It
said
and uh the voice of the trumpets was
exceeding loud and the people were very
afraid. They said all the people in the
camp trembled. Go ahead.
>> And Moses brought forth the people out
of the camp to meet with God and they
stood at the neither part of the mount.
>> And Mount Si was allto together on a
smoke because the Lord descended upon it
in fire. and the smoke thereof ascended
as the smoke of a furnace, and the whole
mount quake greatly.
>> So, we just read that over in Genesis,
didn't we?
Instead, a smoking furnace and um
what was the other thing? A smoking
furnace and uh a fiery oven.
Fiery furnace. But the same thing that
appeared to Abram,
they said that's how the Lord appeared
to Moses.
But go ahead.
>> And when the voice of the trumpet
sounded long and waxed louder and
louder, Moses spake, and God answered
him by a voice.
>> And the Lord came down upon Mount Si on
the top of the mount. And the Lord
called Moses up to the top of the mount.
and Moses went up.
>> So the Lord appeared before the whole
congregation of Israel and he called
Moses up to the top of the mountain.
Let's go to Psalms chapter 81.
Psalms chapter 81.
I'm sorry. Exodus.
Thank you. Thank you.
Moving us moving too fast.
Exodus chapter 20.
I kind of just read this to y'all, but
we can do it again. Y'all ain't got
nowhere to go. Right. Right.
>> Exodus 20 and verse one. The Lord tells
us immediately
why he dwelt in the thick darkness. He
tells us immediately why he dwelt in the
thick darkness. Go ahead, pick it up,
bro.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which hath brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage.
>> So, who's speaking? Is it Is it God or
is it Moses?
>> Oh, the speaking.
>> So, how do we get a Mosaic law if Moses
not the one speaking?
So, whose law is this? It's God's law.
Well, go ahead.
>> Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
>> Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above or that is in the
earth beneath or that is in the water
under the earth.
>> So this is God protecting Israel,
telling them what he don't want them to
do.
Go ahead. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me.
>> Y'all ever heard any minister tell y'all
God was a jealous God. They tell you God
is a God of love. He love everybody.
But we read right here, he say he
jealous. And he visiting iniquity on the
children of Israel. He said to the third
and fourth generation.
I hear people talk about generational
curse. Here it is right here. You keep
working God's commandment and he going
to drop that sword in your household
generation after generation after
generation.
I remember I worked with a guy. He was a
gentile. We was the same age. I had like
eight grandchildren. He didn't have any.
So when he had his first grandchild, I
told him, I said, "Hey man, you got the
opportunity
to break this curse on your family. When
Christmas rolled around, you got the
opportunity to tell your family, we're
not going to indulge in Christmas." He
didn't listen,
but I really didn't expect him to.
You know, that's probably one of the
biggest Christmas he ever had in the
last 50 years because he had his first
grandson.
But go ahead. What verse are we?
>> Verse six.
>> Mhm.
>> And showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
>> So if you want the mercy of God, what do
you need to do? You need to keep his
commandments. And by keeping his
commandments, we showing that we love
him.
That's why we read John 14:15.
If you love me, keep my commandments.
Now, let's turn to Psalms 81.
Psalms chapter 81.
And let's see if God forced the people
to listen to him or did he put a choice
on the table.
I don't think God wants any to force
anyone to love him. He give us all
a choice
to be obedient or disobedient.
Psalms 81 and let's pick it up at verse
8. Psalms 81 and verse 8. Okay, go
ahead. Hear, oh my people, and I will
testify unto thee, oh Israel, if thou
will hearken unto me.
>> The Lord always asking Israel to listen
to him because he know Israel won't
listen.
But he implores us all through the Bible
to listen to him. Go ahead.
>> There shall no strange god be in thee,
neither shalt thou worship any strange
god. Mhm.
>> I am the Lord thy God which brought thee
out of the land of Egypt. Open thy mouth
wide and I will fill it.
>> Mhm.
>> But my people would not hearken on
hearken to my voice and Israel would
none of me.
>> Mhm. So he said my people would not
listen to my voice and they would not
obey me.
So we are very disobedient children
and some of us have raised disobedient
children
and grandchildren.
But go ahead.
>> So I gave them up unto their own hearts
lust and they walked in their own
counselss.
>> So the Lord had he not going to force
anybody to serve him. He said, "I gave
them up to their own lust and to their
own counsel." Hey, you don't want to do
what I want you to do,
then do what you want to do to your own
detriment
because the Bible say you reap what you
sow.
But go ahead.
>> Oh, that my people had hearkened unto me
and Israel had walked in my ways.
>> The Lord is almost plead.
Oh, I just wish that Israel would have
listened to me and walked in my ways.
The blessings that the Lord would have
put on us.
And you go to Deuteronomy the 28th
chapter and you can read about all those
blessings,
but the second half of Deuteronomy 28 is
about all the curses.
But the blessings are contingent on us
keeping the commandments
and the curses come if we don't keep the
commandments.
So I'm sure he had Deuteronomy 28
in the first half of that about the
blessings when he talked uh uh lamented
on Israel saying that oh that my people
would have listened to me
and have walked in my ways. Go ahead. I
should soon have subdued their enemies
and turned my hand against their
adversaries.
>> So, Israel will have no enemies or no
adversaries. Nobody would be against
Israel had they listened to the Lord. Go
ahead.
>> The haters of the Lord should have
submitted themselves unto him, but their
time should have endured forever.
>> So, he said the haters of the Lord would
have submitted themselves to Israel.
But we know that that didn't come to
pass. Correct.
Let's go back. Let's turn back to Exodus
20.
Exodus 20.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
20.
And the Bible going to tell us where
Moses
found the Lord when he came up to the
mount.
Where did Moses
find the Lord when he went up to the top
of the mount? Exodus 20 and 20. Exodus
20 and 20.
So the Lord spoke all the commandments
to the children of Israel, and they
said, "All that the Lord have said will
we do."
>> Okay, brother. Go ahead.
And Moses said unto the people, "Fear
not, for God has come to prove you, and
that he his fear may be before your
faces that you sin not." So
the Bible tell us to fear the Lord is
what? The beginning of wisdom, right? So
if we fear, have fear the Lord, we be
will become wise.
So Moses also equated us being obedient
as not sinning.
Go ahead.
>> And the people stood a far off, and
Moses drew near unto the thick darkness
where God was.
>> So Moses found God in the thick
darkness. Right.
>> Go ahead. And the Lord said unto Moses,
"Thus thou shalt say unto the children
of Israel, Ye have seen that I have
talked with you from heaven." So the
Lord talked to the children of Israel
from heaven. And the Bible asked a
question, have the Lord ever done so
with any other nation?
He never talked to no other nation from
heaven.
But go ahead. You shall not make with me
uh make with me gods of silver, neither
shall you make unto me gods of gold. So
again, he's warning them about making
images,
graven images, and bow down and worship
them. But as usual, Israel did not
listen.
Let's go to Deuteronomy,
the fourth chapter.
Deuteronomy chapter 4
because Exodus
and Deuteronomy
go together
just like Daniel and Revelation
go together.
So let's see were the people allowed to
see God
when he was
dealing with them when they came out of
Egypt. Deuteronomy 4 and let's pick it
up at verse 9. Deuteronomy chapter 4 and
verse number N.
So he starts out telling them asking the
question, "What nation is there so great
to have statutes and judgments
so righteous is all this law which I
have set before you this day." The Lord
asks Israel that go ahead.
Only take heed to thyself, and keep thy
soul diligently, lest thou forget the
things which thine eyes have seen, and
lest thy depart from thy heart all the
days of thy life. But teach them thy
sons and thy sons sons. So the Lord is
telling Israel
to keep their soul diligently to watch
over
their works, the things that they do.
And
don't forget what your eyes have seen.
How could you forget?
How could those people could forget what
they saw God do? How could they forget
seeing him split the Red Sea and them
walking over on dry land?
How could they forget the mountain uh
smoking and quaking and burning with
fires
and hearing the voice of God? How could
they forget those things?
So Moses is telling them, "Teach these
things to your sons and your
grandchildren and your
greatgrandchildren,
your from generation to generation. Go
ahead. especially the day that thou
stood as before the Lord thy God in
Horeb.
When the Lord said unto me, Gather me
the people together, and I will make
them hear my words, that they may learn
to fear me all the days that they shall
live upon the earth, and that they may
teach their children. So that's that's a
simple recipe.
>> Simple. Listen to the Lord, fear him,
and teach his laws, statutes, and
commandments to your children. That's a
recipe for success right there. Not only
success, but for eternal life.
This is what we call the simplicity
of Christ.
But go ahead.
And ye came near and stood under the
mountain, and the mountain burned with
fire unto the midst of heaven, with
darkness, clouds, and thick darkness.
>> And the Lord spake unto you out of the
midst of the fire. You heard the voice
of the words, but saw no similitude,
only ye heard a voice.
>> So they heard the voice of God speaking
out of the clouds and out of the thick
darkness.
They didn't see any shape or form of
God. They only heard his voice.
And that was enough to scare him to
death.
Go ahead.
>> And he declared unto you his covenant
which he commanded you to perform, even
ten commandments. So he said he declared
unto you cuz he spoke to the children of
Israel his covenant which he commanded
you to perform or to do or to keep.
And these this this uh these this this
covenant
is called the ten commandments.
Everybody is familiar with the ten
commandments.
But I bet everybody didn't know that the
ten commandments was God covenant.
Go ahead.
>> And he wrote them upon two tables of
stone.
>> And he wrote those commandments upon two
tables of stone.
God's ten commandments is God's
covenant.
With not only Israel, but with all
mankind,
not even just mankind. As we saw last
week, the covenant, the uh promises, I
mean, the commandments, they was um for
the angels as well
because the ones that broke the covenant
was kicked out of heaven.
Let's go back to Exodus 24.
And like I said last week, they sinned
before man was even created.
So that meant the covenant was already
there.
Exodus 24
and we're going to pick it up in verse
number 12. And we're going to take a
look at how long was Moses
in the mountain in the presence of God.
Exodus 24:12. How long was Moses in the
mountain
in the presence of God?
Okay, brother. Go ahead.
And the Lord said unto Moses, "Come up
to me into the mount and be there, and I
will give thee tables of stone, and a
law, and commandments, which I have
written, that thou mayest teach them."
So, who wrote the commandments?
God said he did, right? So, how you
going to come along and say, "Oh, we
can't keep them. They they ain't no
ain't no good no more."
that was only for Israel. We got all
kind of excuses
that we don't want to keep God's
commandments. He said he wrote them. In
other places say God wrote them with his
own finger.
And when he wrote them in stone, that
kind of meant to me that that means they
unchangeable.
When you write something in stone,
you write on a piece of paper, you can
get you a eraser and erase that.
But you write them in stone. The only
way to change them, you gonna have to
break the stones.
What verse out?
>> 13.
>> Go ahead.
>> And Moses rose up and his minister
Joshua. And Moses went up into the mount
of God. And he said unto the elders,
Tear ye here for us until we come again
unto you. And behold, Aaron and her are
all are with you. If any man have any
matters to do, let him come unto them.
>> And Moses went up into the mount, and a
cloud covered the mount.
>> So when Moses went up, what covered the
mount?
Well, a cloud covered the mountain. Go
ahead.
>> And the glory of the Lord abode upon
Mount Si, and the cloud covered it six
days, and the seventh day he called unto
Moses out of the midst of the cloud.
Mhm.
>> And the sight of the glory of the Lord
was like devouring fire on the top of
the mount in the eyes of the children of
Israel.
>> Mhm.
>> And Moses went into the midst of the
cloud and got him up into the mount. And
Moses was in the mount 40 days and 40
nights.
>> So Moses went up in the mount with God
for 40 days and 40 nights.
And it said that the sight of the glory
of the Lord was like a devouring fire on
top of the mount in the eyes of the
children of Israel. And here Moses
was exposed to this for 40 days
and 40 nights.
Let's go to Exodus 33.
Exodus 33.
And we're going to see during this time
that Moses was in the mount with the
Lord, was Moses able to see God?
Exodus 33. And we're going to pick it up
at verse 17.
Exodus 33 and verse 17.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
And the Lord said unto Moses, I will do
this thing also that thou hast spoken,
for thou hast found grace in my sight,
and I know thee by name.
>> So the uh Moses had wanted to he asked
the Lord to let him see him.
So the Lord says
that he going to allow Moses to do this
thing to see him because he knew Moses
by name. In other places, it said that
Moses that the Lord talked to other
prophets in a dream or in a vision, but
his servant Moses, he spoke to Moses
face to face.
18.
>> And he said, I beseech thee, show me thy
glory.
>> Mhm. Skip down to verse 20.
>> And he said, Thou can not see my face,
for there shall no man see me and live.
So no man could see the face of the Lord
and live.
But
Moses saw everything but God's face.
Go ahead. And the Lord said, "Behold,
there is a place by me, thou shalt stand
upon a rock, and it shall come to pass
while my glory passeth by that I will
put thee in the cliff of the rock, and I
will cover thee with my hand while I
pass by." So it look like God got body
parts, don't he?
But everybody want you to think he just
a puff of smoke,
something with no shape or form.
But if he going to cover Moses with his
hand, then it look like he got some
shape and form to me.
>> Definitely.
>> But go ahead.
>> And I will take away my hand, and thou
shalt see my back parts, but my face
shall not th shall not be seen.
>> So the Lord allowed Moses to see his
back parts.
Let's turn over to the 34th chapter.
of Exodus.
And while Moses were with God was with
God, what happened to Moses face? Exodus
34 and we're going to pick it up at
verse 4.
Go ahead.
>> And he heed two tables of stone like
unto the first. And Moses rose up early
in the morning and went up unto Mount Si
as the Lord had commanded him and took
in his hand the two tables of stone.
>> So why is Moses heing out two tables of
stone like unto the first? Because when
he came down off the mount from getting
the the stones from God,
Israel was sinning.
They had did just what the Lord said
don't do in the second commandment. They
had made a a golden calf,
a golden image, and said, "These be the
gods that brought you out of Egypt, oh
Israel." And when Moses saw it, he broke
the commandments
and killed a whole lot of people, ground
that graven image into powder, put it in
the water, and made the people drink.
Then he began to kill them along with
the Levites.
So this is why he's
hewing out another set of stones because
he broke the first ones. So that's how
important they were to God. He could
have just said, "Okay, well you broke
them. Maybe we'll do something else.
Maybe I should write them on or type
them a letter, make it or make it
handwritten."
But that's not what he did.
So he heed out two tables of stone like
the first.
Go ahead. Verse five.
>> And the Lord descended in the cloud and
stood with him there and proclaimed the
name of the Lord.
>> So then the Lord came down. How did he
come down? He came down in the cloud.
Go ahead. He's still in thick darkness.
Go ahead. And the Lord passed by before
him and proclaimed the Lord, the Lord
God, merciful and gracious,
longsuffering and abundant in goodness
and truth.
>> Skip down to verse 17.
>> Thou shalt make thee no molten gods.
>> Skip down verse 27.
The Lord said unto Moses, "Write thou
these words, for after the tenor of
these words, I have made a covenant with
thee and with Israel." So who writing
these words now? This time Moses got to
write it. But the Lord was telling him
what to write. And he said, "After 10 of
these words, I have made a covenant
with you, Moses, and with the children
of Israel." Go ahead.
And he was there with the Lord 40 days
and 40 nights. And he did neither eat
bread nor drink water. And he wrote upon
the tables the words of the covenant.
The ten commandments. So there it is
again. The words of the covenant. This
time Moses wrote them.
These are the ten commandments. So when
we open up with the reading of the law,
we are reading the words of the covenant
that God made with the children of
Israel.
Go ahead.
>> And it came to pass when Moses came down
from Mount Si with the two tables of
testimony in Moses' hand when he came
down from the mount that Moses was not
that the skin of his face shone while he
w he talked with them. So when Moses
came down off the mountain after 40 days
and 40 nights up there with the Lord,
Moses didn't realize cuz he didn't have
no mirror, but his face was beginning to
shine.
Go ahead.
>> And when Aaron and all the children of
Israel saw Moses, behold, the skin of
his face shone, and they were afraid to
come nigh him.
>> They was afraid when they saw Moses, and
the way his face was shining. And I
wonder how much shine he had on him.
It was more than just a little Vaseline,
wasn't it?
Go ahead.
>> And Moses called unto them and Aaron,
and all the rulers of the congregation
returned unto him, and Moses talked with
them.
>> Skip down to verse 35.
And the children of Israel saw the face
of Moses that the skin of Moses' face
shone. And Moses put the veil upon his
face again until he went in to speak
with him.
>> So Moses was beginning to take on the
characteristics of a spiritual being
just being in the presence of the Lord
40 days and 40 nights.
Because the Bible tell us that spiritual
beings we appear like the sun.
That's why
when the kingdom come, it say there'll
be no need for the sun and the moon
because we going to light it up.
Amen.
Let's turn to Deuteronomy 4.
Deuteronomy chapter 4.
And let's look at the commandment that
that Moses
was urgent for the people to keep.
Which one of the commandments mo did
Moses urge
the people to keep? Deuteronomy 4 and
pick it up at verse 14. Deuteronomy 4
and 14.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> And the Lord commanded me at that time
to teach you statutes and judgments,
that you might do them in the land,
whether you go over to possess it.
Take ye therefore good heed unto
yourselves, for ye saw no manner of
similitude on the day that the Lord
spake unto you and Horeb out of the
midst of the fire. So Moses is telling
the children of Israel to take good heed
to yourselves because you didn't see no
image, no shape of anything
at Horeb
out of the midst of the fire when the
Lord came down.
Go ahead.
lest ye corrupt yourselves and make you
a graven image, the similitude of any
figure, the likeness of male or female.
>> So the L So Moses is telling the people
to take heed that you don't make any
kind of graven image of any figure or
likeness, male or female. Go ahead.
>> The likeness of any beast that is on the
earth. The likeness of any wing foul
that flyth in the air.
>> Mhm. the likeness of anything that
creepeth on the ground, the likeness of
any fish that is in the waters beneath
the earth.
>> Unless thou lift up thine eyes unto
heaven, and when thou seeest the sun,
and the moon, and the stars, even all
the host of heaven, should be driven to
worship them, and serve them, which the
Lord thy God hath divided unto all
nations under the whole heaven.
So Moses was warning the people, don't
make an image of anything. And that's
what the commandment was telling us.
Anything that is in heaven above or in
the earth beneath or in the water under
the earth.
He said, "Unless you be driven to
worship them and serve them." Man didn't
listen, did he?
We got zodiacs. We got horoscopes. We
got all those things that we worship. We
even got crosses and crucifixes that we
wear on our necks.
But Moses was telling the people, don't
do these things.
Go ahead.
>> But the Lord hath taken you and brought
you forth out of the iron furnace, even
out of Egypt, to be unto him a people of
inheritance, as ye are this day. Mhm.
So, but he said, "The Lord had brought
us out of the iron furnace, which was
the slavery that we were up under when
we were down in Egypt,
and he wanted us to be the people of his
inheritance."
At that time, even to today, we are
still the heritage of the Lord.
Let's turn right over to Deuteronomy the
5th chapter.
And Moses is going to recount how the
Lord talked to Israel. Deuteronomy 5 and
verse one. Deuteronomy 5 and verse one.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> And Moses called all Israel and said
unto them, "Hear, O Israel, the statutes
and judgments which I speak in your ears
this day that you may learn them and
keep and do them." So the Lord is
telling Israel that you need to learn
these, keep them, and do them.
>> That's right.
>> That's not the modern teaching today in
the Christian church.
Jesus kept them. So you don't have to.
But that's not what we read, are we?
But go ahead.
>> And the Lord our God made a covenant
with us in
>> Horeb. Mhm.
>> The Lord made not this covenant with our
fathers, but with us, even us, who are
all of us here alive this day.
>> Mhm.
>> The Lord talked with you face to face in
the mount out of the midst of the fire.
>> And we read that, right?
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> I stood between the Lord and you at all
at at that time to show you the word of
the Lord. For ye were afraid by reason
of the fire, and went not up into the
mount, saying, I am the Lord thy God,
which brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, from the house of bondage.
>> Skip uh skip down to verse eight.
>> And showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love
>> Verse eight. Verse eight.
>> Say verse 10.
>> Verse eight.
>> Oh, verse eight. Thou shalt not make
thee any graven image or le any likeness
of anything that is in heaven above or
that is in the earth beneath or that is
in the waters beneath the earth.
>> Mhm.
>> Thou shalt not bow down thyself unto
them, nor serve them. For I the Lord thy
God am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquity of the fathers upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me,
>> and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
>> So God is a even-handed God.
When you obey him, he going to show you
mercy. But when you disobey, he going to
put that generational curse on you.
Skip down to verse 22.
These words the Lord spake unto all your
assembly in the mount out of the midst
of the fire of the cloud and of the
thick darkness with a great voice and he
added no more. And he wrote them in two
tables of stone and delivered them unto
me. So the Lord spoke all those words
out of the thick darkness. And when he
got done speaking he didn't add no more.
And it's written in Deuteronomy said,
"You shall not add to or take away from
the word of God."
So when the Lord got done, that was it.
It was written in stone. We didn't need
no uh like the Constitution, we don't
need to add no amendments to it.
It's complete. Everything we need to get
salvation,
God gave it to us. What verse are we?
>> Verse 23.
>> Go ahead.
>> And it came to pass when he heard the
voice out of the midst of the darkness.
For the mountain did burn with fire.
>> See how the Lord always got that
darkness
>> out of the midst of the darkness. And
the mountain did burn with fire. Same
way when he when he showed up with
Abram,
go ahead.
>> That ye came near unto me, even all the
heads of your tribes and your elders.
>> And ye said, Behold, the Lord our God
has shown us his glory and his
greatness. And we have heard his voice
out of the midst of the fire. We have
seen this day that the God doth talk
with man, and he liveth. Mhm. So he
showed Israel that God does talk to man.
And when the Lord talk to you, you don't
have to die,
especially if you righteous. Now, if you
wicked, it might be another thing.
Go ahead. Now, therefore, why should we
die? For this great fire will consume
us. If we hear the voice of the Lord our
God anymore, then we shall die.
>> Only if you wicked.
For who is there of all flesh that have
heard the voice of the living God
speaking out of the midst of the fire as
we have and live? Nobody.
No other nation that heard the voice of
the Lord speaking out of the midst of
the fire and live. None but Israel.
Let's go to Exodus chapter 25.
Exodus chapter 25. Now the Lord is going
to ask Israel to bring an offering.
And I'm not going to even do that.
I'm not going to ask y'all for an
offering. But the Lord, he asked the
children of Israel to bring him an
offering.
And let's see what they brought him.
Because you know at feast during feast
time
some brothers say well you know you can
bring the lord the offering but he
didn't want you to offer money. He want
you to bring a bring a cow or a sheep or
something like that.
Not in this day and age.
But let's see what happened back then
when the Lord asked them to bring him an
offering. Let's see what they offered.
Uh, Exodus 25 and verse one. When you
get there, brother, go ahead.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
>> who doing the speaking?
>> So, always the Lord speaking to Moses,
right?
Go ahead.
>> Speak unto the children of Israel.
>> Now, who is he speaking to? The nations.
He's speaking to the children of Israel.
This who this Bible is written to, for
and about, the children of Israel.
Go ahead.
>> That they bring me an offering. Of every
man that giveth it willingly with his
heart you shall take my offering.
>> So he wants you to give willingly. Have
a a a willing heart to give. Go ahead.
>> Skip to verse eight.
>> Uh
yeah, skip to verse eight.
>> And let them make me a sanctuary that I
may dwell among them.
And there I will meet with thee, and I
will commune with thee from above the
mercy seat, from between the two
cherubam, which are upon the ark of the
testimony of all things which I will
give thee in commandment unto the
children of Israel. So the Lord, he
going to come down
and sit on the mercy seat.
I'm going to throw this in because I
kind of mentioned it. So, we going to go
back and we going to read just a couple
of verses. Verse three
to see what the what was they bringing
as a offering. I should have I should
have kept that in the lesson.
But we're just going to read a couple uh
verses just to see what they brought.
Start at verse three. Darnell.
>> And thou shalt cast four rings of gold
for it and put
>> Exodus 25 and verse three.
Oh, 30.
>> Oh, it's three. My bad.
And this is the offering which ye shall
take of them. Gold and silver and brass.
>> We ain't got to read no more. This is
the offering you shall bring to me.
Gold, silver, and brass.
They tell you now get rid of your dollar
bills and do what? Buy you some gold.
Buy you some silver.
So the Lord is talking money.
Y'all see these screens we got in here?
We didn't get there with no bull and no
goat and no sheep.
This was done with y'all's tithe money.
The offers that y'all made to the Lord.
>> But let's get back in the lesson.
Numbers nine.
Numbers chapter nine.
And we going to take a look. We're going
to take a look at how uh how Israel was
directed when they left out of Egypt.
See how they was directed when they left
out of Egypt.
Because they was
in the wilderness when they came out of
Egypt.
Numbers 9 and verse 15. Numbers 9 and
15.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> And on the day that the tabernacle was
reared up, the cloud covered the
tabernacle, namely the tent of the
testimony. And that evening there was
upon the tabernacle as it were the
appearance of fire until the morning. So
after they took up this offering for the
Lord, they they built this uh tabernacle
and
um
in the evening they appeared on top of
the tabernacle the appearance of fire
from evening until morning.
Go ahead.
So it was always the cloud covered by
day and the appearance of fire by night.
So this tabernacle
in the daytime a cloud covered,
but in the evening
it was covered by fire.
Skip down to verse 21.
Go ahead.
And so it was when the cloud abode from
evening unto the morning, and that the
cloud was taken up in the morning, that
they journeyed, whether it was by day or
by night, that the cloud was taken up,
they journeyed. So whenever the cloud
came up from between the off the mercy
seat, from between the two cherubims,
Israel began to journey.
So whenever the cloud lifted up off the
mercy seat, Israel would pack up and
they would start to move out. Go ahead.
Or whether it were two days or a month
or a year that the cloud terried upon
the tab tabernacle remaining thereon,
the children of Israel abode in their
tents and journey not. But they when it
was taken up, they journeyed. So no
matter how long the cloud that the Lord
was in there sitting on the mercy seat,
whether it was two days, a month, or a
year, the children of Israel abode in
their tents until the Lord got up off
the mercy seat. Ain't that something?
Let's turn to First Kings the 8th
chapter.
First Kings chapter 8.
We're going to take a look
at what took place when Solomon
he built the temple after they had built
the tabernacle. And when they came into
the land became a nation, then
David had wanted to build a house for
the Lord.
But David has shed so much blood that
the Lord wouldn't let David do it. So
Solomon did it. So Solomon built the
temple to the Lord. And let's see what
happened when Solomon dedicated the
temple to the Lord. First Kings chapter
8, let's pick it up in verse 10. First
Kings chapter 8 and verse 10. When you
get it, brother, go ahead.
>> And it came to pass when the priests
were come up out of out of the holy
place that the cloud filled the house of
the Lord.
>> So when the priests came up out of the
holy place, the cloud, the same cloud we
was reading about in numbers,
it filled
all the house of the Lord. Go ahead.
>> So that the priest could not stand to
minister because of the cloud. For the
glory of the Lord had filled the house
of the Lord.
>> So the glory of the Lord filled the
house of the Lord. Because the Lord was
in the cloud.
Go ahead.
>> Then spake Solomon. The Lord said that
he would dwell in the thick darkness.
I have surely built thee an house to
dwell in, a settled place for thee to
abide in forever.
So
Solomon said that the Lord
said that he would dwell in the thick
darkness. We've been reading that all
afternoon, right? And he said he
assurely built a house for the Lord to
dwell in forever. Although the temple
didn't last forever,
but no temple does, even ours.
Let's go to uh 2 Chronicles
the 6th chapter.
2 Chronicles chapter 6.
I already read it, but I mean said it,
but we're going to read it. Why wasn't
David allowed to build the house of the
Lord?
2 Chronicles 6. And we're going to pick
it up at verse one.
The reason why David was not able to
build the house of the Lord because he
even prophesied about it in Psalms
32nd chapter about finding a dwelling
place for the Lord.
2 Chronicles
chapter 6 verse one. When you get it,
brother go ahead.
>> Then said Solomon, the Lord have said
that he would dwell in the thick
darkness. Mhm.
>> But I have built a house of habitation
for thee, and a place for thy dwelling
forever.
>> Mhm.
>> And the Lord turned his face, and
blessed the whole congregation of
Israel, and all the congregation of
Israel stood.
And he said, "Blessed be the Lord God of
Israel, who have with his hands
fulfilled that which he spake with his
mouth to my father David, saying, Since
the day that I brought forth my people
out of the land of Egypt, I chose no
city among all the tribes of Israel to
build a house in that my name might be
there. Neither chose I any man to be a
ruler over my people Israel."
>> That's good. I didn't see what I was
looking for. I must didn't write it
down. But we know that David, the Lord
would not allow David to build the house
of the Lord because David had shed too
much blood.
I'll get that to y'all next time.
But let's go to Acts
the second chapter.
Acts chapter 2.
I figured y'all was tired of being in
the Old Testament. So, let's throw a
little New Testament in there.
>> Acts 2 and38.
And we're going to look at how we become
part of the new covenant
because we've been reading about the
covenant that the Lord was making
on the in the Old Testament. We're going
to look at how we become part of the new
covenant. Acts 2 and verse 38.
This was after uh Jesus was killed
or crucified,
buried and had risen from the dead.
238. Go ahead, brother.
>> Then Peter said unto them, repent and be
baptized, every one of you, in the name
of Jesus Christ, for the remission of
sins, and ye shall receive the gift of
the Holy Ghost.
>> So this is how you become part of the
new covenant.
First of all, we have to repent
and then we have to be baptized in
water.
in the name of Jesus
to have our past sins washed away.
Then the Lord will give us the gift of
the Holy Spirit.
Go ahead.
For the promise is unto you and to your
children and to all that are far off,
even as many as the Lord our God shall
call. So the promise was to them at that
time to their children and to all those
that are far off, which we are far off
from Acts chapter 2. But
to all those
whom the Lord our God shall call,
because we know that unless the father
draw us,
we can't come to the son.
So I pray
that everybody in here has been drawn by
the father. And how are we drawn? By
this word. Right.
Let's turn to Isaiah 45.
Isaiah 45.
And let's look at the reason we serve
the Lord. Because he is a
creator and a savior.
Not just a creator, but our creator and
savior. Isaiah 45:E1 15.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> Verily thou art a God that hideest
thyself, oh God of Israel, the Savior.
>> So he said, "Verily, you are a God that
hides yourself, oh God of Israel, the
Savior." How does the Lord hide himself?
In thick darkness.
Can you imagine how thick that darkness
have to be? Because the Lord is light.
So that thick darkness blocks out all
that light from allowing us to see him.
But he is a savior. Go ahead.
>> They shall be ashamed and also
confounded all of them. They shall go to
confusion together that are makers of
idols.
>> So if you making an idol, a graven
image, the Lord say you are confused
and confounded and ashamed. Go ahead.
>> But Israel shall be saved in the Lord
with an everlasting salvation.
>> Who going to be saved in the Lord?
>> Israel.
>> Israel. So everybody going to have to
become part of the commonwealth of
Israel if they going to be saved.
Go ahead.
>> You shall not be ashamed nor confounded.
World without end.
>> So if you serving the true and living
God, he said you should not be ashamed
or confounded. But if you worshiping
graven idols that you car with your own
hand, the Lord say you gonna be full of
confusion
and you gonna be confounded. Go ahead.
For thus says the Lord that created the
heavens. God himself that formed the
earth and made it. He hath established
it. He created it not in vain. He formed
it to be inhabited it. I am the Lord and
there is none else. So this God that we
serve, he is a creator as well as a
savior. He created the heavens and he
formed the earth and he made it to be
inhabited. Go ahead.
I have not spoken in secret in a dark
place of the earth. I said not unto the
seed of Jacob, seek me in vain. I the
Lord speak righteousness. I declare
things that are right.
>> That's right. He said, "I have not
spoken in secret in the dark place of
the earth." Even when he was in the
thick darkness in e in uh Egypt, he
didn't speak in secret.
Everybody heard his voice.
>> That's right.
>> And he gave us his covenant.
He gave it unto the seed of Jacob. And
he said, "The seed of Jacob will not
seek him in vain."
Go ahead.
Assemble yourselves and come. Draw near
together, ye that escape of the nations.
>> They have no knowledge that set up the
wood of their graven image, and pray
unto a God that cannot save.
>> So the Lord wants us to assemble
ourselves and come together and escape
of the nations.
We're going to have to leave this place
because these people that have no
knowledge have set up the wood of their
graven image and pray unto God that
cannot save.
That's what they doing.
And the book of Revelation tell us that
they going to make an image that's going
to walk and talk and the world going to
worship that thing. And we can see it's
right around the corner. We got AI,
don't we?
>> Yeah.
>> So, this thing is
possible
sooner than we think.
Let's go to Mark 15.
Mark 15.
We're going to take a take a look at
Jesus death and see
what law did Jesus death on the cross.
What law was eliminated?
Was it the covenant or the ten
commandments that we've been reading
about all afternoon when Jesus died?
That's what
the Christian churches will have you
believe.
But we going to read the book and see
see what it say. Mark 15 and verse 33.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> And when the sixth hour was come, there
was darkness over the whole land until
the 9inth hour.
>> Remember that. From the sixth hour to
the 9inth hour, there was darkness
over the whole land when they crucified
Jesus.
Go ahead.
And at the ninth hour, Jesus cried with
a loud voice, saying, Eli, Eli, lassan,
which is being interpreted, my God, my
God, why hast thou forsaken me? Mhm. So
Jesus cried out to the father, "My God,
my God, why have you forsaken me?" Go
ahead. And some of them that stood by
when they heard it, said, "Behold, he
calleth Elias." And one ran and filled
their sponge full of vinegar, and put it
on a reed, and gave him to drink,
saying, "Let alone, let us see whether
Elias will come to take him down." Mhm.
>> And Jesus cried with a loud voice and
gave up the ghost.
>> So Jesus cried again with a loud voice
and he just simply died. And when he
died, what happened?
>> And the veil of the temple was written
twang from the top to the bottom.
>> So the veil of the temple, it was ripped
in two. Not from the bottom up, but from
the top down, letting you know that no
man could have done that.
>> That's right.
So what did that signify?
It signified the end of animal sacrifice
because the priest stood daily
sprinkling the blood for sinners in
front of that veil.
So once the Jesus died, there was no
more need for the animal sacrifice.
There was no more need for the Levitical
priesthood
because now when Jesus died or rather
when he rose from the dead, now we are
under the priesthood of Mechisedc.
But go ahead.
And when the citorum which stood over
against him saw that he so cried out and
gave up the ghost, he said, "Truly this
man was the son of God." So this Roman
centurion that witnessed this, he said,
"Truly
this man was the son of God."
But let's turn to Psalms 18
and let's see
what happened
that this was prophesied
by David
about the passion of Christ.
And when he cried out, "My God, my God,
why have you forsaken me?"
Let's see what happened.
Psalms 18, we're going to pick it up at
verse three. Psalms 18
and verse number three.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
I will call upon the Lord who is worthy
to be praised. So shall I be saved from
my enemies.
>> The sorrows of death compass me, and the
floods of ungodly men made me afraid.
>> Mhm. I'mma tell y'all right now and keep
it in mind as we read through this. This
is not David.
This is not talking about David, but
David is prophesying
about what's going to happen to the
Messiah.
Go ahead. The sorrows of hell compass me
about. The snares of death prevented me.
In my distress, I called upon the Lord
and cried unto my God, and he heard my
voice out of his temper. Mhm.
>> And my cry came before him, even into
his ears.
>> Mhm. So the Lord's cry went all the way
up to the third heaven, and the father
heard his cry. And then what happened?
>> Then the earth shook and trembled. The
foundations also of the hills moved and
were shaking because he was raw.
>> Mhm.
>> There went up a smoke out of his
nostrils, and fire out of his mouth
devoured. coals were kindled by him.
>> He bowed the heavens also and came down
and darkness was under his feet.
>> So this is the father coming down
to reassure Jesus that everything was
going according to plan
and he came down. That's why it got dark
from the ninth out
because the father
bowed the heavens and came down
and it said darkness was under his feet.
Go ahead. How did he how was he
traveling?
>> And he rolled upon the cherub and did
fly. So he was riding on a chair and he
flew. Go ahead.
>> Yeah, he did fly upon the wings of the
wind.
>> He flew flew upon the wings of the wind.
Go ahead.
>> He made darkness his secret place.
>> His pavilion round about him were dark
waters and thick clouds of the sky.
>> At the brightness that was before him,
his thick clouds passed by. hailstones
and coals of fire.
>> The Lord also thundered in the heavens
and the highest gave his voice hail
stones and coals of fire.
>> So
the father came down in darkness in
thick darkness. And that's why when the
Lord died on the cross, what was it from
the ninth hour? What what hour was it?
From the sixth hour to the to the to the
ninth hour, it was dark because the
father came down to reassure Jesus that
everything was going to be okay.
Don't forget in three days, in three
nights, you're going to return to your
former glory.
You're going to be God again,
and you will have redeemed the creation.
because you have made the ultimate
sacrifice
for the children that you have created.
Not only that, you have destroyed
the enemy which is Satan
because you have made that blood
sacrifice,
the atonement,
and now
the children have access back to the
tree of life.
So, he let Jesus know all of that,
but he came down
to deliver the message.
Let's go to Matthew 27. Ain't that
something?
Give me goosebumps.
Matthew 27
and verse 45.
This is a fulfillment
of Psalms 18,
Matthew 27 and verse 45.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> Now from the sixth hour, there was
darkness over all the land until the 9th
hour. Mhm.
>> And about the ninth hour, Jesus cried
with a loud voice, saying, "Eli, Eli,
lama sabakan." That is to say, "My God,
my God, why hast thou forsaken me?" So
the father had to let Jesus know,
"You're not forsaken."
Their flush was on Jesus. You can't
blame him for feeling that way. Go
ahead.
>> That was the end of that.
>> Oh, that was the end of that. Okay. All
right. So, that's what we wanted. He's
that was fulfilled in Jesus that David
wrote over there in in Psalms the 18th
chapter. Now let's go back to Psalm
chapter 97.
Psalms 97.
We just going to read a little bit about
the response of nature.
The response of nature at the coming of
the Lord. How does nature respond
at the coming of the Lord? Psalms 97 and
we're going to pick it up at verse one.
You get it, brother. Go ahead.
>> The Lord reignth. Let the earth rejoice.
Let the multitude of isles be glad
thereof.
>> Mhm. So he said, "The Lord reigns. Let
the earth rejoice and the multitude of
the islands be glad thereof." Go ahead.
>> Clouds and darkness are round about him.
>> What's around about the Lord? Say clouds
and darkness is around the Lord. Right.
Go ahead.
>> Righteousness and judgment are the
habitation of his throne.
>> And righteousness and judgment is where
his th his throne
abides at. That's his habitation. Go
ahead. A fire goeth before him and
burneth up his enemies round about.
>> His lightnings enlightened the world.
The earth saw and tremble.
>> Mhm. So when the earth saw this, it
trembled. Go ahead.
>> His light Oh, the hills melted like wax
at the presence of the Lord. At the
presence of the Lord of the whole earth.
>> So look at how nature is respond
responding to the presence of the Lord.
Go ahead.
>> The heavens declare his righteousness
and all the people see his glory.
and all the people see his glory. It say
Revelation say every eye going to see
him. Right.
Go ahead.
>> Confounded be all they that serve graven
images that boast themselves of idols.
Worship him all ye gods.
>> So again, there it is. Those that
worship idols, he said they going to be
confounded. They are confounded and
confused.
They boast themselves in idols. And he
said, "All ye gods," see that with a
little G, "All ye gods, worship the
Lord."
Let's go to Exodus 10.
Exodus 10.
I think it was in last week's lesson
when we read about the Exodus when the
uh death angel came in at midnight after
the children of Israel had put the blood
over the doorpost
and the death angel came through and
passed over all the houses with the
blood on their door post and that angel
Angel was caused the called the
destroyer.
So
let's see who sent this angel
of darkness into Egypt. Exodus 10 and
verse 21. Exodus 10 and 21.
When you get it, brother, go ahead. And
the Lord said unto Moses, "Thest out thy
hand toward heaven, that there may be
darkness over the land of Egypt, even
darkness which may be felt." So
that's awfully dark, ain't it? It's a
darkness that can even be felt.
You ever been in the dark before? Went
down in a dark basement and just you
just walking and feeling so you don't
bump into nothing.
It was darker than that.
>> And Moses stretched forth his hand
toward heaven, and there was a thick
darkness in all the land of Egypt, three
days.
>> So this thick darkness that Moses called
on, it was over the whole land of Egypt
for three days. Go ahead.
>> They saw not one another, neither rose
any from his place for three days. So
they couldn't even see each other. You
in the in the room with your wife. It's
so dark you can't even see your wife.
You can't see your kids. That's how dark
it is. I can't even wrap my mind around
that.
>> But go ahead.
>> But all the children of Israel had light
in their dwellings.
>> But the children of Israel, they all had
light in their dwellings.
Let's look at it again. Psalms 105.
Let's see how the Lord did this thing.
Psalms 105
and verse number 26.
So we just talking about this thick
darkness
that our Lord used
to keep us from
creating idols and images to bow down
and worship
because he hid himself
from mankind so that we would not sin
and make a graven image saying this is
God and bow down to him.
Psalms 105, we're going to pick it up at
verse number 26. Psalms 105 and verse
26. Okay, brother, go ahead.
>> He sent Moses his servant and Aaron whom
he had chosen. They showed his signs
among them and wonders in the land of
Ham.
>> So the land of Ham is Egypt. And the
Lord showed his signs to Moses and Aaron
that he had chosen and sent them under
Pharaoh to deliver the children of
Israel out of bondage. Go ahead.
>> He sent darkness and made it dark and
they rebelled not against his word.
>> So the Lord, he sent darkness and made
it dark. And when that happened, he said
they did not rebel against his word. Go
ahead.
>> I stand.
>> Oh, that's it. All right. That's what I
wanted. The Lord sent darkness and made
it dark. That's what we just read about
in Exodus the 10th chapter. Let's go to
Psalms
78.
Psalm 78.
Then I got two more places after this.
We're going to read one verse in verse
78.
I mean in Psalm 78
and the plagues that the Lord sent on
Egypt,
this is how they was accomplished. Psalm
and verse number N. Psalm 78
49. Thank you
and verse 49.
So all the plagues that the Lord sent,
the frogs and the darkness and the hail
and the hot thunderbolts and the flies,
all those
plagues that the Lord sent. This is how
he did it. Go ahead, brother. Verse 49.
>> He cast upon them the fierceness of his
anger, wrath, and indignation, and
trouble by sending evil angels among
them. So the Lord did all that. All
those plagues in Egypt, even the last
plague, the death of the firstborn,
it was done by sending evil angels
among them.
Ain't that something?
Let's go to Hebrews. And we know the
most evil angel
was Lucifer himself.
and he still ain't finished
trying to sift us as we
Hebrews 12,
we're going to pick it up at verse 18.
Hebrews 12 and 18.
And we're going to let Paul
tell us about
when the Lord appeared to Moses in Mount
Horeb.
Because the Bible, as we know, we go
here a little and there a little.
And this is how we find out that a fact
is established.
Hebrews 12 and verse 18. When you get
it, brother, go ahead.
For ye are not come unto the mount that
might be touched, and that burn with
fire, nor unto blackness, and darkness,
and tempest,
and the sound of a trumpet, and the
voice of words, which voice they had
that they that heard and treated, that
the word should not be spoken to them
anymore.
>> That's what Israel said. Don't let God
speak to us no more, Moses. You speak to
us and we shall listen.
>> For they could not endure that which was
commanded.
And if so much as beasts touched the
mountain, it shall be stoned or thrust
through with the dark.
>> Mhm.
>> And so terrible was the sight that Moses
said, I exceeding exceedingly fear the
quake.
Read one more.
But ye are come unto Mount Zion, and
unto the city of the living God, the
heavenly Jerusalem, and to an
innumerable company of angels. So
to the
>> Lord, that's good.
>> So the Lord say he have an innumerable
amount of angels. But even back here,
uh, Paul is letting us know how the Lord
appeared in Egypt to the children of
Israel and what it looked like, how the
mountain burned with fire and how it was
black and dark.
So, let's go to our last place,
Zephaniah.
the book of Zephaniah,
the first chapter,
and we're going to look at the coming of
the Lord, which is called the day of the
Lord.
Zephaniah 1 and we're going to pick it
up in verse 14.
Zephaniah 1 and verse 14.
the day, the day of the Lord. And this
is how it's going to come in.
Zephaniah 1 and14.
When you get it, brother, go ahead.
>> The great day of the Lord is near. It is
near and hasteth greatly. Even the voice
of the day of the Lord, the mighty man
shall cry there bitterly.
>> That day is a day of wrath. So the day
of the Lord is a day of wrath.
Go ahead.
>> A day of trouble and distress.
>> A day of trouble and distress. Go ahead.
>> A day of wastess and desolation. A day
of darkness.
>> Oh, it's a day of darkness, too.
>> And glooiness.
>> A day of clouds and thick darkness.
Let's get down to verse 17.
And I will bring distress upon men that
they shall walk like blind men because
they have sinned against the Lord and
their blood shall be poured out as dust
and their flesh as the dawn.
>> So he said he will bring distress upon
men that they should walk like blind men
because they have sin sin against God.
Just like when uh the uh men of Sodom
and Gomorrah was trying to get to the
angels that was in Lot's home and the
angels blinded them, but that didn't
stop them from still trying to find the
door. But they was groping in the
darkness. And that's how it's going to
be when the Lord come that men will walk
like blind men because they have sinned
against God.
Last verse.
>> Neither their silver nor their gold
shall be able to deliver them in the day
of the Lord's wrath. So if you rich, you
got money, silver, and gold in the day
of the Lord's wrath,
it ain't going to matter. It will not
deliver you. Go ahead.
>> But the whole land shall be devoured by
the fire of his jealousy. For he shall
make even a speedy riddens of all them
that dwell in the land.
>> Amen.
So brothers and sisters, in conclusion,
the Bible, the biblical accounts of
God's power and presence is revealed
through nature, prophecy, and historical
events.
It highlights scriptures where David and
other prophets describe the passion of
Christ, the fulfillment of prophecy in
the Gospels,
and nature's dramatic response to God's
appearance.
The scriptures discuss the plagues of
Egypt, the Lord's manifestation in
darkness and reflect and reflects on the
significance of these events in both the
old and new testament writings. So
brothers and sisters, I give you our our
God dwells in the thick darkness.
This helps us to keep the second
commandment. I hope you learned
something and I thank you for your time.
Oh,
hey.